Guide to the Bayrd Still Papers MC.44
New York University Archives
Bayrd Still Papers
1926-1988
1950-1980
New York University Archives
Still, Bayrd
MC.44
65.94 Linear Feet in 59 record cartons, 5 manuscript boxes, 4 oversize flat boxes, one square box, 3 card boxes, and 3 folders in a shared flat box.
From 1947 to 1987, Bayrd Still served New York University (NYU) as historian, archivist, teacher, and administrator. An authority on urban history and development, Still also studied landmark preservation in New York City. This collection documents Still's professional life at NYU. It also contains some personal materials.
Conditions Governing Access
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Given to University Archives by Bayrd Still in 1985. One student notebook in Series VIII was transferred to the University Archives in 1993 by Fred Schult, the Director of Undergraduate Studies in the Department of History. It was added to Series I, Subseries D, of this collection in 2016. The accession number related to this collection is 85.033.
Materials found in Series III: NYC Research, Subseries D: Mirror For Gotham Research Materials were transferred from the New York University Archives Photograph Collection (PHOTO.00001) in May 2024. The accession number associated with this accretion is 2024.031.
Arrangement
Materials are largely in their original order. Most folders are arranged chronologically. Within the folders the material is arranged chronologically in descending order. Some arrangement was imposed by archivists when original order was not known, or materials had been separated from the rest of the collection, as in Series VI through VIII.
The collection is arranged into 8 series and 19 subseries:
Series I: Subject, Historical Reference, and Personal Files
Subseries A: Subject Files
Subseries B: Historical Reference Files
Subseries C: Personal Current Papers (Restricted)
Subseries D: Personal Notebooks
Series II: Research, Committees, Talks, Reviews, Still's Articles
Subseries A: Published Sources
Subseries B: Original Research
Subseries C: Published Sources
Subseries D: NYU Committees
Subseries E: Talks, Reviews
Subseries F: Partial Collection of Articles in Historical Journals
Series III: NYC Research
Subseries A: Landmarks
Subseries B: Research on NYC
Subseries C: Sources about Urbanism and Urban Development
Subseries D: Mirror For Gotham Research Materials
Series IV: Speeches, Reviews, Doctoral Student Files, Mayoral Research, NYU Archives
Subseries A: Speeches, Reviews, Press
Subseries B: Doctoral Students (Restricted)
Subseries C: Mayoral Research
Subseries D: Archives, Talks, and Articles
Series V: Correspondence
Subseries A: Correspondence
Subseries B: NYC Research
Series VI: Landmarks
Series VII: Copper Photo Engravings
Series VIII: Books on New York City and Urban America
Biographical Note
From 1947 to 1987, Dr. Bayrd Still served New York University (NYU) as historian, archivist, teacher, and administrator. An authority on urban history and urban development, Dr. Still's interests and commitments extended beyond his academic research and the university to involve landmark preservation in New York City.
Bayrd Still was born on July 7, 1906, in Woodstock, Illinois. He received bachelor's, master's, and doctoral degrees in history from the University of Wisconsin. Before assuming his professorship at NYU, Still taught at Ohio Wesleyan University, the University of Wisconsin, and Duke University.
From 1947 to 1974 Dr. Still was a professor at NYU in the Department of History, for which he also served as chair from 1955-1970. In 1955 Still was appointed head of the undergraduate history department at University College as well as head of the graduate program of history. In 1957 he became head of the all-university Department of History and remained so until 1970. Additionally, he served as acting dean for both the undergraduate College of Arts and Sciences and the Graduate School of Arts and Science from 1958-1959, and again from 1959 to 1960. Throughout his teaching career, Still taught at both the University Heights campus and the Washington Square campus.
President James M. Hester established the Office of the Archivist in 1967, appointing Thomas C. Pollock as University Archivist, and Bayrd Still as Chair of the Advisory Committee on the History of New York University. The committee helped to write the NYU history. When Pollock resigned in 1969, Still declined the position of University Archivist, continuing instead as chair of the Advisory Committee. He played a key role in the founding of the University Archives project until 1975, when he became University Archivist.
Still was an authority on United States urban development and westward expansion. Courses he taught included "The History of the American City since 1820" and "The History of New York City." His publications include: Urban America: A History with Documents, Milwaukee, The History of a City, Mirror for Gotham: New York as Seen by Contemporaries from Dutch Days to the Present, and The West: Contemporary Records of America's Expansion Across the Continent, 1609-1890.
In 1961 Still served as supervisor for New York University graduate fellowships with the New York Community Trust. In 1962 Mayor Robert F. Wagner appointed Still to the Landmarks Preservation Commission, a position he held until 1965. Still also served on the Mayor's Task Force on Municipal Archives in New York. In 1975 he became the Chairman of the Advisory Board for the Brooklyn Rediscovery Project. He was a member of the New-York Historical Society, the American Studies Association, and the Society of American Historians. In the 1980s Still organized and conducted walking tours of NYU and Greenwich Village. Dr. Still died in Woodstock, Illinois, on November 19, 1992.
Sources:
New York Community Trust, "The Heritage of New York". (New York: Fordham University Press): xviii
Kald, Milt "Meeting The Guardian of NYU's Past." Washington Square News. (September 29, 1980): 3
Bayrd Still: vita
Related Materials
Records of the Office of the President (James M. Hester) (RG 3.0.7)
Scope and Contents
The bulk of this collection documents Dr. Bayrd Still's professional life and work as a historian of New York City and urban America, a professor of history at New York University, and as a New York University Archivist. The collection contains correspondence; published and unpublished articles and speeches; historical research materials; photographs; and information regarding Still's professional associations and early career. A series of copper engraving plates, prints from which were included in Still's book A Mirror for Gotham (New York University Press, 1956), and a series of books annotated by Still are also included in the collection.
Correspondence.; Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.); Manuscripts for publication.; historical maps.; Brooklyn Heights (New York, N.Y.).; Historic buildings -- New York (State) -- New York.; Copper engraving.; Speeches.; Photographs.; Clippings (information artifacts); New York (N.Y.) -- History; Hayes, Ralph; New York University. Council; Platt, Geoffrey, 1905-1985; Wagner, Robert F. (Robert Ferdinand), 1910-1991; Heald, Henry T. (Henry Townley), 1904-1975; New York University -- Faculty -- History; New York Community Trust; New York University -- Curricula -- History; New York (N.Y.). Landmarks Preservation Commission; New York (N.Y.). Committee for the Preservation of Structures of Historical and Esthetic Importance
- Series I: Subject, Historical Reference, and Personal Files, 1933-1988
  Scope and Contents
  Series I materials reflect Still's professional and personal involvement with NYU and New York City.
  - Subseries A: Subject Files, 1937-1979
    Subseries A: Subject Files covers Still's work with other historians and includes materials on conferences, talks, interviews, and other special events; projects such as the Albert Gallatin Papers Project; and Still's duties at New York University.
    - American Historical Association (A.H.A.) Session, Dec. 30, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General note
      3 1142 04225046 7
    - A.H.A. Session, Dec. 29, 1950, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - A.H.A. Meeting, Dec. 28 - Dec. 30, 1954, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - A.H.A. Session, Dec. 28, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Pacific Coast Branch, A.H.A. --- Session, Sep. 1, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - A.H.A. Session, Dec. 30, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - A.H.A. Session, Dec. 29, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Census, A.H.A. and M.V.H.A. Committee on, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Organization of American Historians (O.A.H.) Session, Apr. 28, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - O.A.H. Session, Apr. 14, 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Progressive Education Association Regional Conference, Apr. 9, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Mississippi Valley Historical Association (M.V.H.A.) Session, Apr. 25, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - M.V.H.A. Session, May 2, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Problems of an Urban Biographer," Talk, Milwaukee County Historical Society, Mar. 4, 1967, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - "Suggestions for a Municipal Archive," ca. 1940 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Gallatin Papers Project, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bobst Library; Elmer Bobst, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bobst Library Guy E. Still Seminar Room, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Tucker, Louis, State Historian, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Columbia University Colloquium on City in American History, 1966-67, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - "Statehood Process," Reprint of article on, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - History Seminar Room, Gift of, for History Seminars, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Gifts to N.Y.U., 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Heffer, Jean, American Council of Learned Societies Scholar, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Kenan Chair in History, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Cartter House (34 West 11th Street), History of, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Town and Davis, Firm of, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Saveth, Edward, "Understanding the American Past," Evaluation of, for Little, Brown and Co., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225047 5
    - Sussex Tapes, 1972-1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - "Crisis in the City" Newark State College Workshop, Apr. 19, 1968, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Query of Simon and Schuster re History of New York City, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Still and Klebanow, "The Teaching of American Urban History," JOURNAL OF AMERICAN HISTORY (March, 1969) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Speech to Students from France, Aug. 5, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Norfolk Division of Virginia State College, Advisory Work for, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Reid, John P., American Legal History, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Gallatin Associates, Committee Work, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Query from Little, Brown and Co. re Urban book, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Buildings in New York City, Information on, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - South Street Seaport, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Conference on National Archives and Urban Research, Jun. 18, 19, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - McGraw-Hill, Manuscripts read for, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - PRAIRIE FARMER description of Milwaukee for WISCONSIN MAGAZINE OF HISTORY, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "Urban History in the Schools," Speech, Bloomsburg State College, Nov. 21, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Taylor, Moses, Fund for Biographical Research; Moses Taylor Fellowship, 1954-1977 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Community Trust Landmarks Plaques Project, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Welfare Department, New York City - History of Organizational Structure, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Walking Tours - Lower City, 1975-1977 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Walking Tours - Greenwich Village, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Greenwich Village Maps, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Washington Square North -- Robert C. Weinberg Description, 1962-1969 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Walking Tour - Campus, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225048 3
    - C.W. Post College Talk, "The Record-Keeping Role of the Librarian as a Contribution to Community Life," February 15, 1972, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - C.W. Post College, First Annual Archives Institute, Nov. 13, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Schnore, Leo, "The New Urban History" Evaluation for University of Wisconsin Press, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Greenwich Village: Living Landmarks Landmarks Celebration Week, Sep. 29, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Greenwich Village Historical Society, Proposal for, Jan. 3, 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Qualifying Exams in American History and Urban History, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Bicentennial Corporation (N.Y.C.), Historical Committee, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - N.Y.U. Bicentennial Committee - Minutes and Reports, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Greenwich Village - Architectural and Historical Guide, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Bicentennial (U.S.) Exhibit at N.Y.U., undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Bicentennial Corporation (N.Y.C.), Documentation, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Bicentennial Corporation (N.Y.C.), Archives Inventory, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Bicentennial Corporation (N.Y.C.), Pamphlet Series, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Bicentennial Corporation (N.Y.C.), Greenwich Village Bicentennial Exhibition Council, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - O'Dwyer, Paul - Efforts on behalf of New York City history, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225049 1
    - HERALD TRIBUNE Morgue, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Columbia University Seminar on the City, 1974-1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Columbia University Seminar on the City Workshop on Teaching of Urban History, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Honorary Degree Citation for Barbara Tuchman, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Society of American Historians, 1972-1978 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Dean's Advisory Committee on Tamiment Library, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Sonfist, Alan - Project on Natural Identity of New York City, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Brooklyn City Seminar at Long Island University, Talk, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Queens College Advisory Committee of the Historical Documents Collection, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - JOURNAL OF URBAN HISTORY, 1973-1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - "Greenwich Village in Historical Perspective," Talk, March 20, 1974, in Margot Gayle's Continuing Education Course, "Vanishing New York" (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - New Jersey Historical Commission Commission Program, Dec. 7, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "Greenwich Village Landmarks -- the History of the University's Neighborhood," Speech, Alumni Brunch, May 5, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Greenwich Village Landmarks - the University's Historic Neighborhood" Remarks, Heights College Alumni Association, May 3, 1975, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "A Slide Tour Through Greenwich Village," Speech, Faculty Woman's Club, Nov. 18, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Class Night Address, University College, Jun. 7, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Norton, Perry L. - Urban Planning History, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Bellagio Study and Conference Center, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Corwin, Raymond, "America, It's All the Difference" -- Consultation on script, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - NEW YORK, THE CENTENNIAL YEARS, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Fulbright-Hays Program -- Advisory Committee, 1974-1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225050 9
    - Bergen Community College: TV Series. Science, Technology, and Urban Life. Taped May 19, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - WCBS-TV Bicentennial Calendar; Jill Gelbach, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Civitas Club, Brooklyn - Speech, Jan. 9, 1976, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - American Museum of Immigration, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Bicentennial Corporation (N.Y.C.), Heritage Trail Advisory Committee, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "History at N.Y.U." History Department Bicentennial Observance, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Bridgeport, University of - Center for Urban-Suburban Studies, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Committee on New York University's Response to the New York City Fiscal Crisis, Prof. H. J. Weiner, Chairman, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Stave, Bruce, Interview for JOURNAL OF URBAN HISTORY, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Stern, Ilana, Oral history interview with Bayrd Still, Mar. 19, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - ESSAYS IN THE HISTORY OF NEW YORK CITY, Irwin Yellowitz, editor, 1975-1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Lunenfeld, Marvin, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Walking Tour, Lower City, for students from Lake Forest College, February, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "New York in 1827" Speech, Ascension Church, Oct. 18, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - HISTORIAN (May, 1977), "Introduction" for (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Phi Alpha Theta - Regional Meeting, at St. Joseph's College, Slide Lecture, "Greenwich Village", 1977 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Bronx County Historical Society, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Balakian, Anna (Comparative Literature Seminar) Walking Tour, Greenwich Village, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Brooklyn Rediscovery - Work as Chairman of the Board of Advisors, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Talk on New York City to Presidential Scholars, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "Traditions at N.Y.U.," W.S.U.C. Orientation Talk, Sep. 20, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Lehman, Orin Luncheon, Nov. 13, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Astor Place Subway Renovation Steering Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Municipal Art Society - Carole Rifkind, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Grand Central Terminal Exhibit, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225051 7
    - Arts and Humanities Citation Index, Policy Advisory Board, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - "New York in 1829: The City a Century and a Half Ago" Speech, College Conference on New York History, Apr. 20, 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "The Suburban Village, 1820-1860" - Forum on History of Greenwich Village, May 10, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "New York City 150 Years Ago: The Urban Scene in 1829" Speech, New-York Historical Society, Nov. 13, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Cantor, Mindy, "Around the Square," Sesquicentennial Proposal, undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Class of 1929 Speech, Commencement, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Varick House, Effort to Preserve, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Feature Film Project, A.H.A. Committee on, 1968-1971 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Archives of American Art - Advisory Committee, 1962-1966 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Four-course Plan, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Phelps Lectures, 1929-1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Acting Dean, Graduate School of Arts and Science, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225052 5
    - Dean's Day (G.S.A.S.), Feb. 27, 1971, Remarks (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Chambers of Commerce, History of, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Books on individual cities, as of 1939, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - City Charters Comparisons - Buffalo, Cleveland, Detroit, Chicago, Milwaukee, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Cleveland Mayors and Council members, 1836-77, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Mayor, Office of, in the U.S., MUNICIPAL AFFAIRS, III (1899), undated (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Commencement Address, Woodstock (Ill.) Community High School, Jun. 8, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "Processes and Problems of Mid- 19th Century Urbanization" - Paper, M.V.H.A. session, May 2, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "Cooperative Research in Local History" Paper, A.H.A. session, Dec. 30, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "Milwaukee, 1870-1910" Paper, M.V.H.A. session, Apr. 25, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "Comment," Local History Session, A.H.A., Dec. 31, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Milwaukee, Analysis of City Directories, 1847-1938, listing city officials and occupations thereof, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Milwaukee, Contemporary Description of, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Examination Questions (Graduate), 1951-1974 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "Travels in Hot Weather," WESTERN MONTHLY MAGAZINE, July to December, 1834, an account of travel, mainly in Kentucky, presumably in about 1833, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - "Travels in Hot Weather," typed excerpts, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Turner, Frederick Jackson, Autobiographical letter; reference to "safety valve", undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225053 3
    - "Travels in Hot Weather," typed excerpts (carbons), undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Turner, Frederick Jackson, Interpretations of, undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Curti, Merle, Conclusions of Trempealeau County Study, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - U.S. History Course, 1961, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Social and Economic History of the U.S. (University College), undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - West in American History - Lecture and Colloquium Schedules, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - City Course - Reserve Book List, 1947-1951 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Still-Klebanow, "The City in American History: A Selective Bibliography", undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - City Course - Lecture and Colloquium Schedules, 1967-1970 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Seminar, Materials for, 1970-1973 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Seminar on New York City History - Topics, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - New York City, History of, Bibliography, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - All-University Departments (General), 1957-1961 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - History Department, Notes for history of, 1939-1976 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - History Department - Important Documents, 1953-1976 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Nomination of F. L. Paxson for President of A.H.A., 1936 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Paxson FESTSCHRIFT correspondence, 1936-1938 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Project UHEAR (Oral Urban History), 1971 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "New York University and Its Neighborhood Tradition," - Article, ALUMNI NEWS, October, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Bicentennial (U.S.) Observance - Copy for Exhibit Folder, undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Remarks at Retirement of Joseph H. Park, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Mailing Privilege (second class), N.Y.U., Testimony to Protect, undated (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Long Island University Urban Affairs Conference program, 1963 March 8-10 (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - "History at New York University, 1831-1976," by Bayrd Still (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Elmer Holmes Bobst Library tote bag, undated (Box 70)
      ID Number: 206. Description: Bobst Library, The black-, tan-, and rust-colored canvas bag is 13 x 11 x 4.5. Creator/Donor/Subject: Bayrd Still Collection.
  - Subseries B: Historical Reference Files, 1933-1988
    Subseries B: Historical Reference Files contains Still's research on the history of New York University and its relationship to New York City. It is missing a number of folders that were noted in the original inventory of the collection provided to the University Archives by Still.
    - Academic programs, early, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      3 1142 04225054 1
    - Administrative charts and lists of administrators, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Benefactors and supporters, early, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)